# Nicole A. Jaffke, MS

3040 Adams Ave, Unit 5. | San Diego, CA 92116 | 847.363.0264 | Nicole.jaffke@gmail.com https://github.com/nicolejaffke

#### **SUMMARY:**

Knowledgeable, front-end website developer/UX specialist looking to utilize my healthcare background in the tech industry. Years of work experience as a successful business owner, physical therapist, and personal trainer. Supportive and enthusiastic team player with 10 years of leadership experience. Self-motivated engineer with a passion for learning. Always striving to be on the cutting edge of new technology. Quick learner and able to attack new tasks confidently and efficiently.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

January 2021-

## **Affinity Therapy**

San Diego, CA

Present

Founder/Owner, Physical Therapist Assistant, Personal Trainer

- Oversee day to day tasks of the business including building/maintaining the website, marketing, social media, outreach, scheduling, patient organization, and customer service
- Evaluate, assess, and manually treat orthopedic injuries on a wide variety of patients in an outpatient orthopedic clinic setting for over 200 active patients
- Business growth in one year: doubled revenue, tripled the number of active patients, initiated online programming/training/therapy, optimized SEO to bring in new leads

January 2021-Present

## **HealthStream Physical Therapy**

San Diego, CA

Supervisor, Physical Therapist Assistant (Remote)

- Utilize technology to administer telehealth therapy services
- Lead and nurture a team of therapists, chair monthly meetings, employ documentation review, examine invoices, create microsoft office spreadsheets and docs for efficiency of the business.
- Built HealthStream from a 2 person team to a 12 person team in 18 months

March 2020-December 2020

#### Vida Health

San Diego, CA

r 2020 Health Coach (Remote)

- Provide web-based coaching services via various platforms (Doxy, JaneApp, GoogleDocs)
- Facilitated a panel of clients seeking health in order to prevent and treat chronic illnesses, utilizing motivational interviewing techniques to engage members

May 2019-December 2020

#### **Nexus Physical Therapy**

San Diego, CA

Clinic Manager, Physical Therapist Assistant, Certified Athletic Trainer

- Coordinated the day-to-day tasks associated with the Sports Arena clinic including collaboration between clinicians and patients, cultivating a positive team atmosphere within staff, meeting financial goals, and regulating compliance.
- Provided medical services including examination, diagnosis & treatment of injuries

September 2017-May 2019

#### **Podium Sports Performance**

Upland, CA

Athletic Trainer

• Sustained athletes' physical well-being through the use of therapy treatments & rehabilitation

September 2013-April 2017

## **Marquette University Valley Fields**

Milwaukee, WI

Supervisor

• Coordinated team of student workers to operate Division 1 athletic events

# **Personal Projects:**

Personal Portfolio https://nicolejaffkeportfolio.netlify.app/	Weather App https://nicolesweatherapp.netlify.app/
Wedding Website https://nicoleandchris2023.weddingwoo.com/	Affinity Therapy https://www.affinitytherapywithnicole.com/

### **EDUCATION:**

SheCodes Pro Bootcamp	<b>Azusa Pacific University,</b> Azusa, CA	Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI
Front End Web Developer	Master of Science in Athletic Training	Bachelor of Science in Exercise Physiology

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, Git, Hosting, Flexbox, Ajax, SEO, Responsive Design/Development, UX Design, UI development, Figma, Invision

## **CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES:**

2022-Present	SheCodes Plus: Front End Web Developer
2022-Present	SheCodes React: React Development
2022-Present	SheCodes Responsive: Responsive Web Development
2022-Present	FreeCodeCamp Web Development Certification
2022-Present	FreeCodeCamp Javascript Certification
2020-Present	Licensed Physical Therapist Assistant from the Physical Therapy Board of CA and TX
2019-Present	Certified Athletic Trainer from the Board of Certification
2017-Present	National Council of Certified Personal Trainers certification (CPT)
2013-Present	American Red Cross First Aid and CPR Certification

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:**

Competitive Marathon runner: Completed 12 marathons and serve as a leader in a sub-elite running team (Prado Racing Team).